3par.com 2012-05-11

# Online privacy statement | HP

## HP respects your privacy

HP and its subsidiaries respect your privacy. This Privacy Statement informs you of our privacy practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. This statement is readily available on our home page and at the bottom of every HP Web page.

HP was a founding sponsor of the Council of Better Business Bureau’s Online Privacy Program and is a BBB Accredited Business. HP privacy practices are consistent with the BBB Code of Business Practices and we proudly display the BBB seal.

In the development of HP’s privacy policies and standards, we respect and take into account the major principles and frameworks around the world, including the OECD Guidelines on the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows, EU Directive 95/46/EC, APEC Privacy Framework, and the Madrid Resolution on International Privacy Standards.

HP has self-certified its privacy practices as consistent with U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor principles: Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Access and Accuracy, Security, and Oversight/Enforcement. More information about the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. [](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/). HP has also established a set of binding corporate rules (“BCR”), which have been approved by all Data Protection Regulators in the EEA and Switzerland effective June 2011. The BCRs ensure that personal data of covered individuals in the EEA is adequately protected while being processed by any of HP’s global entities.

In compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles and BCR requirements, HP commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. HP has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints from EU citizens or residents regarding transfers of their personal data under the Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU Safe Harbor, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if HP does not satisfactorily address your complaint, you may contact BBB EU Safe Harbor at: <http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints>. [](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints)

HP has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of personal information. TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trust mark and innovative trust solutions. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through any software downloaded from this Web site. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact HP using the contact information included at the end of this statement. If you are not satisfied with our response, you can contact TRUSTe here. 

  * Scope of this Privacy Statement 
  * Collection of personal information 
  * How we use your information 
  * How we share your information 
  * Children's privacy 
  * Your choices and selecting your privacy preferences
  * Access to and accuracy of your information 
  * Keeping your information secure 
  * Changes to this statement 
  * Contacting us

How HP uses automatic data collection tools:

  * Cookies
  * Web beacons
  * Embedded web links
  * HP ads on third party websites

## 1\. Scope of this Privacy Statement

HP is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. This Privacy Statement applies to all HP-owned websites, domains, services, applications, and products, and those of our wholly owned subsidiaries ("HP sites or services"), except that a privacy policy or statement specific to a particular HP program, product, or service may supersede or supplement this Privacy Statement.

## Links to non-HP websites

HP sites or services may provide links to third-party applications, products, services, or websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the HP site. HP does not control those third party sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from HP's practices. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party sites. The personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by the HP Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any site you interact with before allowing the collection and use of your personal information.

We may also provide social media features that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with HP on various social media sites. Your use of these features may result in the collection or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and settings on the social media sites with which you interact to make sure you understand the information that may be collected, used, and shared by those sites.

## 2\. Collection of personal information

HP collects, exports, and uses personal information to better serve you and personalize your experience and interaction with HP. Such collection is done with appropriate notice and consent, along with required filings with data protection authorities, where applicable. 

HP may collect personal information from you to complete various transactions, such as:

  * product or service orders, activations, and registrations
  * profile creation
  * information requests
  * marketing or support subscriptions
  * contest entries or survey participation
  * instant credit applications
  * job applications

The types of personal information you provide to us may include:

  * contact information, such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address
  * financial information, such as your credit card number
  * other unique information such as user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, product and service preferences, contact preferences, educational and employment background, and job interest data

If you apply for instant credit, we may ask you to provide additional personal information such as salary, social security number, banking information, and other information to authenticate you and verify credit worthiness. This information will be used by our financial services providers in determining whether to extend you credit. 

If you choose to use a “tell-a-friend” or a similar referral program on our site, we will ask you for your friend’s e-mail address, mobile phone number, or other contact information and automatically send your friend a one-time message inviting your friend to visit the site. HP uses and stores this information only for the purpose of sending this one-time message and to provide tell-a-friend message blocking, where available.

If you post, comment, indicate interest, or share personal information, including photographs, to any public forum on an HP site, social network, blog, or other such forum, please be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, viewed, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to contact you, send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes that neither you nor HP have control over. HP is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

In addition to the information you provide, HP may also collect information during your visit to an HP website, or a website “powered by” another company on behalf of HP, through our Automatic Data Collection Tools, which include Web beacons, cookies, and embedded Web links. These tools collect certain traffic information that your browser sends to a website, such as your browser type and language, access times, and the address of the website from which you arrived. They may also collect information about your Internet Protocol (IP) address, unique device identifier, clickstream behavior (i.e. the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with HP websites or “powered by” websites) and product information. HP may also use some of these Automatic Data Collection Tools in connection with certain emails and communications sent from HP and therefore may collect information using these tools when you open the email or click on a link contained in the email. To learn more, read How HP uses automatic data collection tools.

HP also collects information from commercially available sources that it deems credible. Such information may include your name, address, email address, preferences, interests, and demographic/profile data. The information HP collects from its commercial sources may be used along with the information HP collects when you visit HP’s sites. For example, HP may compare the geographic information acquired from commercial sources with the IP address collected by Automatic Data Collection Tools to derive your general geographic area.

## 3\. How we use your information

The information HP collects to understand your needs and interests helps HP deliver a consistent and personalized experience. For example, HP may use your information to 

  * assist you in completing a transaction or order
  * prevent and detect security threats, fraud or other malicious activity
  * communicate with you about products and services
  * provide and improve service and support
  * update you on new services and benefits
  * provide personalized promotional offers
  * select content to be communicated to you
  * personalize some HP websites
  * measure performance of marketing initiatives, ads, and websites “powered by” another company on HP’s behalf
  * allow you to participate in contests and surveys
  * contact you regarding HP products or services.

We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding the communications we send (see Your choices and selecting your privacy preferences).

The testimonials posted on our Web site are only posted with the expressed permission of the individual or company who provided that testimonial.

Credit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. Credit card information and other sensitive personal information required to process a credit decision is not used for any other purpose by our financial services providers or HP and will not be kept longer than necessary for providing the services, unless you ask us to retain your credit card information for future purchases.

## 4\. How we share your information

HP will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others except as described in this Statement. HP shares personal information in the following ways:

HP retains service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products, services and customer solutions and to assist HP with marketing and communication initiatives. These providers and suppliers include, for example, credit card processors, providers of customer support and live-help, marketing, email service providers, automated data processors, and shipping agents. Suppliers and service providers are required by contract to keep confidential the information received on behalf of HP and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for HP.

From time to time, HP participates in marketing initiatives with other companies, including websites “powered by” another company on behalf of HP. As part of these initiatives, certain HP services and marketing communications may be delivered at the same time as those from other companies. Some of these services and communications offer you the option to share personal information with both HP and the other companies participating in these initiatives. For example, you may receive marketing communications from HP and other companies or have the opportunity to register online for software products from multiple companies. If you choose to provide personal information only to HP, HP will not share this information with the other companies participating in that marketing initiative. If you choose to provide personal information to the other companies, that personal information will be handled according to the privacy policy of those companies, which may differ from HP’s policies and practices.

HP will require the export of your personal information to other HP-owned business entities in the US and Worldwide in accordance with this Statement to satisfy your request. Such export is a requirement of providing the information to HP.

Except as described in this Statement, HP will not share the personal information you provide to HP with non-HP third parties without your permission, unless to: (i) respond to duly authorized information requests of police and governmental authorities; (ii) comply with any law, regulation, subpoena, or court order; (iii) investigate and help prevent security threats, fraud or other malicious activity; (iv) enforce/protect the rights and properties of HP or its subsidiaries; or (v) protect the rights or personal safety of HP employees and third parties on or using HP property. 

Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons, HP decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or the receipt of it from sellers. It is HP’s practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

## 5\. Children's privacy

HP does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and does not target its websites to children under 13. We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online and mobile activities and interests. 

## 6\. Your choices and selecting your privacy preferences

HP gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information that complements our products and services. You can subscribe to receive certain product- and service-specific information and also choose to receive HP general communications. We give you a choice regarding delivery of HP general communications by postal mail, email, telephone, and mobile device. 

You can make or change your choices about receiving either subscription or general communications at the data collection point or by using other methods, which are listed in the following sections. This option does not apply to communications primarily for the purpose of administering order completion, contracts, support, product safety warnings, driver updates, or other administrative and transactional notices as the primary purpose of these communications is not promotional in nature.   

The communications that you receive from HP will be provided in accordance with this statement. Some communications may utilize automatic data collection tools. To learn more, read How HP uses automatic data collection tools.

## Subscription communications

Subscription communications include email newsletters, software updates, etc. that may be expressly requested by you or which you consented to receive. After you request such communications, you may opt out of receiving them by using one of the following methods: 

  * Select the email "opt out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each email subscription communication.
  * To unsubscribe from messages delivered to mobile devices, reply to the message with the words “STOP” or “END.”
  * Return to the Web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions. Access to many HP subscriptions is available at the [Subscriber's Choice web page](http://www.hp.com/united-states/subscribe/gateway/).
  * Write to the [HP Privacy Office](https://h41268.www4.hp.com/live/index.aspx?qid=11507). Be sure to provide your name, relevant contact information, and specific relevant information about the HP subscriptions that you no longer wish to receive.

Please be aware that when you opt out of receiving certain subscription communications, it may affect the services you have chosen to receive from HP where accepting the communications is a condition of receiving the services. 

## HP general communications

HP general communications provide information about products, services, and/or support. This may include new product information, special offers, or invitations to participate in market research. 

You will often be able to use [HP Passport](https://passport2.hp.com/hppcf/modifyuser.do?hpappid=privacy) to indicate whether you want to receive general communications from HP. HP Passport is a single-login service that lets you register with HP Passport-enabled websites using a single-user identifier and password of your choice. HP Passport uses cookies to store your basic personal information so you don't have to retype it when you return to one of HP's many websites in the future. HP Passport also allows you to set your privacy preferences. Your preferences will apply across HP websites, email, and other communication vehicles that use HP Passport.

If you are unable to use HP Passport, you may opt out of receiving these general communications by using one of the following methods: 

  * Select the email "opt out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each email communication.
  * To unsubscribe from messages delivered to mobile devices, reply to the message with the words “STOP” or “END.”
  * Write to the [HP Privacy Office](https://h41268.www4.hp.com/live/index.aspx?qid=11507). Be sure to provide your name, relevant contact information, and specific relevant information about your privacy preferences. 

## 7\. Access to and accuracy of your information

HP strives to keep your personal information accurately recorded. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to help maintain data accuracy. HP provides individuals with reasonable access to personal information that they provided to HP and the reasonable ability to review and correct it or ask for anonymization, blockage, or deletion, as applicable. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. To view and change the personal information that you directly provided to HP you can return to the Web page where you originally submitted your data and follow the instructions on that Web page, use [HP Passport](https://passport2.hp.com/hppcf/modifyuser.do?hpappid=privacy) where enabled, or contact the [HP Privacy Office](https://h41268.www4.hp.com/live/index.aspx?qid=11507).

## 8\. Keeping your personal information secure

HP takes seriously the trust you place in us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, HP utilizes reasonable and appropriate physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect. HP retains data only as required or permitted by local law and while it has a legitimate business purpose.

When collecting or transferring sensitive information such as credit card information we use a variety of additional security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. The personal information you provide us is stored on computer systems located in controlled facilities which have limited access. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as credit card number or password) over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Credit card numbers are used only for processing payments and are not used for other purposes. As part of real-time payment processing, HP subscribes to a fraud management service. This service gives you and HP an extra level of security to guard against credit card fraud and to protect your financial data. 

## 9\. Changes to this statement

If we modify our Privacy Statement, we will post the revised statement here, with an updated revision date. If we make significant changes to our statement, we may also notify you by other means, such as sending an email or posting a notice on our corporate website and/or social media pages.

## 10\. Contacting us

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our Privacy Statement, please send them to the [HP Privacy Office](https://h41268.www4.hp.com/live/index.aspx?qid=11507) or write to us at the following address:

**Canada** **, Most of Latin American, and US:**   
HP Privacy Mailbox   
11445 Compaq Center Drive W.   
Mailstop 040307   
Houston, Texas 77070   
USA 

**Mexico:**   
Hewlett-Packard   
Legal Department  
Prolongación Reforma No. 700   
Colonia Lomas de Santa Fe   
México, D.F., C.P.01210 

**Europe, Middle East, and Africa:**   
EMEA Privacy Office   
Hewlett Packard   
MS 250   
1 Avenue du Canada   
HP Les Ulis -91947 – France 

**Asia-Pacific and Japan:**   
HP APJ Privacy Office   
Hewlett Packard   
PO Box 384   
Concord West, NSW 2138  
Australia

Rev. November 2011

## How HP uses automatic data collection tools

The following sections provide additional information about commonly-used web technology tools.

## Cookies

A “cookie” is a small data file transferred by a website to your computer’s hard drive. HP or its service providers send cookies when you surf our site or sites where our ads appear, make purchases, request or personalize information, or register yourself for certain services. Accepting the cookies used on our site, sites that are “powered by” another company on HP’s behalf, or sites where our ads appear may give us access to information about your browsing behavior, which we may use to personalize your experience. Cookies are typically classified as either “session” cookies or “persistent” cookies. 

  * Session cookies do not stay on your computer after you close your browser.
  * Persistent cookies remain on your computer until you delete them or they expire. Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser. If you turn off cookies, there may be some features of our site that will not be available to you and some Web pages may not display properly.

You can find information on popular browsers and how to adjust your cookie preferences at the following websites: 

From time to time, HP will use Flash local shared objects (LSOs) to store Flash content information and preferences. LSOs perform similar functions to HTML browser cookies and deposit small files on your computer, which are commonly called Flash cookies. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies and cookie management tools provided by your browser may not remove Flash cookies. To learn more about Flash Cookies and how to manage the related privacy and storage settings, please visit the [Adobe Systems website ](http://www.adobe.com/). 

## Web beacons

Some HP.com and third-party Web pages and HTML-formatted email use Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about your website usage and your interaction with email, as well as to measure performance on hp.com and websites “powered by” another company on HP’s behalf. A Web beacon is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1x1) or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on your computer such as cookies, the time and date of a page viewed, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. Depending on the context, web beacons may also refer to content on a third-party server, and may be used by service providers to deliver relevant advertising to you.

You may be able to disable Web beacons in email messages by not downloading images contained in the message you receive (this feature varies depending on the email software used on your personal computer). However, doing this may not always disable a Web beacon or other automatic data collection tools in the email message due to specific email software capabilities. For more information about this, please refer to the information provided by your email software or service provider.

If you choose to receive marketing emails or newsletters from HP as specified in Your choices and selecting your privacy preferences, HP may automatically collect personal information about you. For example, through Web beacons and personalized URLs embedded in these emails or newsletters, HP can track whether you’ve opened those messages and whether you’ve clicked on links contained within those messages. For more information on embedded Web links, see below.

## Embeded Web links

Emails from HP, Internet keyboard keys preconfigured by HP, and promotional icons preinstalled on your PC desktop often use links designed to lead you to a relevant area on the Web, after redirection through HP’s servers. The redirection system allows HP to change the destination URL of these links, if necessary, and to determine the effectiveness of our marketing initiatives. 

In emails, such web links may also allow HP to determine whether you have clicked a link in an email, and this information about the interaction may be connected to your personal identity. If you do not want HP to collect information about the links that you click, you can: 

  * change your choice about how you receive communications from HP (i.e. choose a text-based version of the message where available) or choose not to click links in an email that HP sends
  * delete the promotional icons preinstalled by HP on your PC desktop or choose not to click on those
  * reconfigure the Internet keyboard keys on certain PC models to launch a destination URL of your choice by using the instructions provided with your PC

## HP ads and offerings on third-party websites

HP contracts with service providers to place ads on websites owned by third parties. In addition, some websites may be “powered by” a service provider to provide HP offers on HP’s behalf. These service providers may send cookies from and use Web beacons on these third-party websites and on hp.com. The cookies and Web beacons may enable HP to collect information about the pages you viewed and the links you clicked.

You can learn more about network advertising and how to opt out by visiting [http://www.aboutads.info ](http://www.aboutads.info/).

## Additional information about webOS devices 

In addition to the collection and usage practices described in the HP Online Privacy Statement, this information applies to webOS and the software and services associated with webOS. HP collects and uses webOS-specific information in the following ways: 

  * **Account Set-Up.** If you set up an account to receive services we provide through your webOS device, we will collect your name, phone number, email address and account settings to process your registration and provide those services. 
  * **On-Device Services.** If you use services we provide through your webOS device, we will collect information relevant to providing the services and as you designate. For example:
    * **Device Diagnostics, Analytics and Updates.** In order to improve our product and service offerings, your webOS device includes remote diagnostics, analytics, and software update services. Your webOS device collects technical information related to your device (including serial number, unique device identifier, diagnostic information, usage and crash logs, application configurations, etc.) as required to help identify and troubleshoot issues, and to provide and improve service.
    * **Back-up and Restore.** When you use a back-up and restore service for data stored on your device, we will automatically and regularly collect information related to your contacts, calendar, tasks, email and messaging, including online account usernames; account credentials and settings; memos; text/MMS/IM messages and conversations; phone call logs; web bookmarks and cookies; installed App Catalog applications; and preferences, including Location Service preferences to help enable retrieval of that data when restoring or replacing your device. Additional details, including how to turn “off’ the feature can be found at Using Backup.
    * **Location-Based Services.** When you use location-based services, we will collect, transmit, maintain, process, and use your location and usage data (including both real time geographic information and information that can be used to approximate location) in order to provide location-based and related services, and to enhance your device experience.

You may choose whether or not to provide your personal information to us. If you choose not to do so, you may not be able to take advantage of certain webOS products, services, offers, or options that depend on personal information. 

For your convenience and information, webOS devices may provide links to third-party websites or include applications from third parties. HP does not control those third-party sites or applications, nor does HP control their privacy practices, which may differ from HP's practices. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites or applications. The personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company you interact with before allowing the collection your personal information.

Because HP operates globally, information we gather may be made available to our worldwide business units and subsidiaries. If you are in the European Economic Area, please note that the personal information you provide will be transferred outside the European Economic Area for use by HP and its affiliates and subsidiaries for the purposes described above. By using webOS devices, HP websites, registering for an account or service, or otherwise providing us with your personal information, you consent to this transfer of your personal information. 

Back to top
